GREGORY VANDER SCHUEREN RESUME

Software Engineer

Status: R&D Engineer, Tessares

Fields: Software Engineering, Computer Networking

Interests: Linux, Kubernetes, Cloud-native computing, Networking, DevOps

Languages: Golang, C, Bash, Ruby, Python

29 yrs old, Brussels, Belgium www.linkedin.com/in/gregory-vander-schueren-29747340 gregory.vanderschueren@gmail.com +32 495 51 77 21

Summary

Software engineer with 5+ yrs experience. Graduated both in Computer Science and Business Administration. Experienced in designing and developing complex computer systems. Adept of DevOps and CI/CD tooling and best-practices. Strong background in business, management, entrepreneurship with excellent communication skills. I understand the business language and believe that software should serve the business needs.

Experience

HAG-VNF Engineer - Tessares

2019 - present

- · Architecture, prototyping and implementation of Tessares HAG as a VNF (Virtual Network Function) using Cloud Native principles and technologies (Kubernetes OpenStack, Heat, Prometheus, Fluentd, Elasticsearch, Jaeger, custom k8s operators, gRPC, etc).
- · Wrote Tessares's XDP-based (eBPF) layer 4 load-balancer powering our HAG-VNF.
- · Contributing to Tessares standardization efforts to push the "O-RTT TCP Convert" protocol at the IETF. Wrote lib-convert, together with Gregory Detal, the first open-source implementation. Added support into Tessares' closed source HAG.

R&D Engineer - Tessares

2017 - 2019

- · Development and maintenance of Tessares's Hybrid Access Gateyway (HAG), a performance critical layer 4 proxy that provides Hybrid Internet access to hundreds of thousands of households.
- · Troubleshooting and bug-fixing Tessares's custom Linux kernel, a patched version of the open-source Linux Multipath TCP Kernel implementation.
- \cdot Part-time research work in collaboration with Olivier Bonaventure's research team at the IP Networking Lab of UCL (Catholic University of Louvain).

Full-stack Engineer & Co-Founder - Famest

2012 - 2014

- · Photo sharing social network for fashionistas. 230.000€ in funding from Meusinvest & business angels.
- · Ruby on Rails, iOS, web front-end, hosted on AWS. Application with 100K+ users and 1M+ photos.

Education

Computer Science, Master Degree - Louvain School of Engineering

2015 - 2017

- · Graduated top 1 of my promotion (Summa Cum Laude).
- · Specialization in Security and Networking. Master Thesis: TCPSnitch, dissecting the socket API usage.

Computer Science, Bachelor Degree - Louvain School of Engineering

2014 - 2015

· Completed this 3-years program at an accelerated pace in 1 year (Magna Cum Laude).

Management, Master Degree - Louvain School of Management

2011 - 2013

- · Graduated top 1 of my promotion for the second year of master (18.52/20 GPA), while I co-founded Famest S.A.
- · Specialization in entrepreneurship, cross-disciplinary master program (CPME).
- · Exchange semester at the University of Texas at Austin. Perfect GPA (4.0).

Economics & Management, Bachelor Degree - Catholic University of Louvain

2008 - 2011